# 秋天的第一块糕点
# One of the most popular cakes in Autumn.
# 什么都没加 栗子的本味
# Only natural flavour from chestnut, nothing added.
# 大爷不用我管您就吃上了 好吃
# Da Ye, that’s right, just help yourself. Yummy!
# 您得一块儿搁嘴里头
# You got to eat it in one go.
# 您看看它干甜不干甜
# Sweet or not, try it yourself.
# 凉水下锅 四十分钟捞出来 剥了它
# Peel off their shells after total 40 mins boiling time.
# 拿过生栗子来给它铰个口
# Don’t forget open an end on each chestnut before cooking.
# 到时候好剥皮 行了这就知道了
# So, it is easier to peel. I see.
# 把它剥出来 很面啊
# Take it out. So soft.
# 我把它捣碎一下 这么一碾
# Ground them in a mortar.
# 基本捣的差不多了
# Nearly done.
# 行了我过箩
# Ok. Press through the sieve.
# 我这还有点 提前我给你弄出来的
I also prepared some for you early.
# 你师父太伟大了
# Your master is a great guy.
# 你看见没有 过箩就非常细
# See? It’s so fine after sieving.
# 你再看看这个 全是颗粒
# Look at those, still coarse.
# 为什么说要过箩啊
# That’s why using sieve.
# 就是拿勺碾压 秋天吃这个正好
# Use spoon to press. Perfect season for this delicacy.
# 好了 够了这不要了
# That’s enough. Thank you.
# 看看这个大爷 非常细腻
# Look, Da Ye. So fine.
# 往这里边加上松子仁 搁一块
# Mix with pine nuts.
# 这松子仁事先要炸一下吗 炸一下
# Do you need to deep fry the pine nuts beforehand? Yes.
# 糖桂花
# Add osmanthus sugar syrup.
# 松子仁炸到一上色就赶紧出来
# Take the pine nuts out as soon as they change colour when you deep frying.
# 松子仁生的都好吃
# Even raw pine nuts are nice to eat.
# 稍微一炸就行
# Just quickly fry them.
# 拌成这种 绿豆糕似的那种形式
# Mix them and the texture should look like mung bean cake mix.
# 这个不能使劲压
# Don’t press it too hard.
# 它才有栗子这种干松劲儿
# So, it retains fluffiness.
# 这个做法其实还是很简单
# Actually, the technique is very simple.
# 轻轻一压 一提
# Gentle press, then lift.
# 这不就是栗子糕就出来了
# Here it is. A Chestnut and Pine Nut pressed-cake!
# 大爷你看栗子糕
# Da Ye, look, a Chestnut Pressed cake.
# 什么季节吃什么东西
# Seasonal recipe uses seasonal food.
# 这不就是时令的
# Perfect season for this.
# 家里尤其有小朋友 多有成就感
# Don’t you feel a sense of achievement, particularly in front of the kids?
# 这个为什么叫栗子糕
# It is called Chestnut pressed cake.
# 它有栗子这种干松劲儿
# Because it comes from fluffiness of the Chestnuts.
# 大爷不用我管您都吃上了 好吃
# Da Ye, that’s right. Just help yourself. Tasty!
# 大爷吃完了说两句吧
# What do you think, Da Ye?
# 干 就一个字 干
# Fluffy! One word! Fluffy!
# 香 糯 干 甜
# Fragrant, soft, fluffy and sweet.
# 什么都没加 栗子的本味
# Chestnuts’ natural flavour. Nothing added.
# 完全完全都是原生态
# Completely natural.
# 我建议 在增加口感这方面
# I suggest adding something to the taste.
# 略微的拌一点砂糖
# Mix in a little bit of sugar.
# 主要要增加一个
# Mainly to add
# 砂糖那种脆脆的口感
# crunchiness.
# 应季美食 又是文化的传承
# Seasonal delicacy. Also, a part of culture heritage.
# 牛
# Awesome.
# 好开始 有网友问
# Let’s get started. Some people ask.
# 想听两位大师
# 讲讲各种酱的专题知识
# Could you please share some knowledge of various paste?
# 括弧在我的观念里
# In my memory,
# 只有二伯做炸酱的时候
# 使用的三种酱
# Er Bai only used three types of paste when he made that fried sauce.
# 最近看虎皮鸡爪
# 又出来一种柱候酱
# Recently, there is another Chu Hou paste.
# 想知道各中区别
# What is the difference?
# 用处是什么
# And how to use it?
# 北方我们常见的就是一个黄酱
# The most popular yellow soyabean paste is from north.
# 北京产的天津产的
# Made in Beijing or Tianjin.
# 还有东北产的
# And from north east of China.
# 还有山东产的
# Also made in Shandong.
# 主要在华北地区这一带
# Mainly in greater northern region.
# 黄酱味道也不同
# However, the yellow soyabean paste has various flavour.
# 另外现在出现了一些黄豆酱
# Nowadays, there is a different kind of soyabean sauce.
# 颜色比较暗 浅
# Darker colour, light in texture.
# 不是那么厚重
Not so heavy.
# （但是）颗颗粒粒
# (but) coarse texture wise.
# 都能见到黄豆
# You can see individual yellow soyabean.
# 还有甜面酱
# Also, ‘Tian Mian Jiang’- fermented flour paste.
# 像我们吃烤鸭
# Used in Peking Duck.
# 京酱肉丝
# Shredded pork in Peking sauce.
# 炒一些菜
# 加点甜面酱
# Add a little ‘Tian Mian Jiang’ in some stir fries.
# 所有的酱在运用当中
# 要灵活要巧妙
# Use various paste smartly in cooking.
# 你看二伯炸了一个牛肉蘑菇酱
# For example,
# 他就巧用了我们北方的蒜蓉辣酱
# Er Bai used Northerners’ garlic and chilli paste cleverly in Beef and Mushroom sauce recipe.
# 甜面酱和黄酱 巧妙的结合
# Wonderful combination of ‘Tian Mian Jiang’ and yellow soyabean paste.
# 加上调味当中的这种变化
# Together with seasoning.
# 加上辅料的这种形成那酱炸出来就好吃
# And other ingredients, forming a delicious sauce.
# 有的说老北京的炸酱面
# Some mentioned Zhajiangmian (Fried sauce noodles).
# 谁家的正宗
# Who is the most authentic?
# 谁家也谈不上什么正宗
# Nobody!
# 就是你那酱 炸出来一定要香 润
# Your sauce must be fragrant, moist,
# 有味道
# And flavoursome.
# 喜欢吃这种味
# If you like the taste,
# 这个酱就是好
# Then, it is a nice sauce.
# 没有什么特殊的标准
# There is no particular standard.
# 除了北方的酱 菜的酱的
# In spite of the pastes produced in northern region,
# 全面性
# Overall
# 还是以粤菜为主
# The most varieties of paste can be seen in Guangdong cuisine.
# 不光有煲仔酱
# Not only seafood sauce,
# 柱侯酱
# Chu Hou paste,
# 海鲜酱
# Hoisin sauce,
# 排骨酱
# Spare rib sauce,
# 沙爹酱 沙茶酱
# Satay sauce, Sa Cha sauce,
# XO酱等等
# XO sauce and so on.
# 吃烧腊就柱候酱
# Roasting dishes use Chu Hou sauce.
# 它每个酱的用途不一样
# Different sauce has different usage.
# 将近有二十来种
# Nearly 20 varieties.
# 我们的菜系
# 跟粤菜的菜系出来那个酱
# Different cuisine has different flavour.
# 比如说做一个八珍豆腐坡
# 它那种柱候酱
# Using Chu Hou paste as an example,
# 那种浓浓的这种香味
# 我们别的是替代不了的
# The flavour is irreplaceable when used in a specific dish.
# 你包括每个酱的配比
# Every paste has proportionated ingredients
# 它都是有方的
# It is based on formulas.
# 然后炒这些东西
# Then you stir fry with the paste.
# 这是死的酱方
# The formula is fixed.
# 瑶柱酱都是平的要是一斤都一斤
# XO酱爆虾球
# For an example, Quick fried King Prawn with XO sauce.
# 爆螺片
# 火候一定要到位
# The heat must be powerful enough.
# 所以说用酱的话
# Therefore, the point of using those pastes is…
# 最主要的目的是
# The most important point is that
# 不管用什么酱都是 增香 增味 增稠
# They enhance the flavour and taste.
# 好
# Great!